So now that we have some of the basics of hard head down,
现在我们已经掌握了 Hardhat 的一些基础知识
let's go ahead and try doing some of the same things we did with ethers before but with hard hat.
让我们继续使用 Hardhat 来做一些之前用 ethers 做过的相同的事
So one of the first things we want to do is
我们首先要做的一件事就是
we want to write and interact with our smart contracts.
编写我们的智能合约并与之交互
So let's go ahead and rename greeter dot soul to simple storage dot soul,
所以让我们把 "Greeter.sol" 重命名为 "SimpleStorage.sol"
you can click on the file and hit enter
你可以选中文件并按下回车
and should be able to rename it.
然后你就能重命名它了(译者注：在 Windows 和 Linux 系统中通常是按 F2)
Otherwise, you can go ahead and right click, delete it,
不然，你也可以右键选中，选择删除
and then create a new file and call it simple storage dot soul.
然后创建一个新文件命名为 "SimpleStorage.sol"
We're going to copy paste
我们要复制粘贴
all of our code from our previous simple storage that saw into this file,
之前的 "SimpleStorage.sol" 里的所有代码到这个文件中
we can make sure that our simple storage is compiling correctly
我们要确保 "SimpleStorage" 正确编译
by running yarn hardhat compile.
使用 "yarn hardhat compile"
Whoa, it looks like we ran into an issue
哇，看来我们遇到了问题
project cannot be compiled. See reasons below
项目无法被编译，看看下面的原因
the solidity pragma version of the file. It doesn't match any of the configured compilers in your config.
文件中的 Solidity pragma 版本无法匹配您配置中的任何编译器
Hmm, well, what's going on
好吧，到底是什么问题
contracts slash symbol storage that's Sol zero point 8.8.
"contracts/SimpleStorage.sol(0.8.8)"
Ah, okay, let's go ahead and fix them.
行吧，让我们解决一下这个问题
So we can open up our hard hat dot config dot j s.
打开我们的 "hardhat.config.js"
Now a quick note on opening files. If you're on Mac and you hit Command P,
现在要说一个打开文件的快速说明，如果你在 Mac 上按下 "Command P"
you can actually start typing in the names of files to get them to them quicker.
那么你可以输入文件的名字以快速打开它们
Or if you're on Linux or Windows, you can type Ctrl p,
或者如果你用的是 Linux 或 Windows，那么按下的是 "Ctrl P"
this will bring up and interestingly if you type man P or ctrl p and then you hit the greater than key.
有意思的是，如果你按下 "Command P" 或 "Ctrl P" 并输入“大于键”(">")
This will drop you into the command palette,
它就会把你带到命令面板
know command palette, command palette,
不是命令面板，是命令面板
search for files, search for commands
查找文件，查找命令
in our Hardhead dot config. Jas, I'm gonna scroll down to module dot exports and change this to zero point 8.8.
在我们的 "hardhat.config.js" 里，向下滚动到 "module.exports" 并把这里改成 "0.8.8"
So that the version that we're going to compile
这样我们用于编译的版本
for simple storage, it's gonna be the same version and that hard hat is looking for.
就和 "SimpleStorage" 要在 Hardhat 中寻找的版本相同了
Let's run that same command by just hitting up yarn Hardhead compile,
让我们再次运行相同的命令 "yarn hardhat compile"
and awesome we see compiled one solidity file successfully.
很好，我们看到“成功编译 1 个 Solidity 文件”
We should now see this in artifacts.
现在我们应该就能在 "artifacts" 中看到它了
If we go to artifacts and contracts.
如果我们进入 "artifacts" 以及 "contracts"
We now see two contracts in here, greater and simple storage
可以看到这里现在有两个合约了 "Greeter" 和 "SimpleStorage"
and we can see a ton of the information about simple storage
我们可以看到有关 "SimpleStorage" 的大量信息
we can also see some more lower level in Information and build info.
还可以在 "build-info" 中看到一些更底层的信息
Alright, so now that we have our simple storage contract in here,
好了，现在我们这里就已经有了 "SimpleStorage" 合约
the next thing we probably want to do is learn how to deploy it.
下一件事就是要学习如何部署它了
This is where we're going to write our deploy script.
这里就是我们编写部署脚本的地方
Now, for this section, I'm going to be showing you how to write a deploy script.
现在这一节，我会向你展示如何编写部署脚本
But in the next section, we're going to do it a little bit differently.
但下一节，我们会采用一些不同的方案
But this is still going to teach you how to write scripts and worked with scripts in heart app.
不过这仍然能教会你如何在 Hardhat 中编写和使用脚本
So we're going to come to our sample script dot j s,
所以来到我们的 "sample-script.js"
and we're gonna go ahead and hit enter and renamed it to deploy dot j s.
然后按回车把它重命名为 "deploy.js"
And if you want to read all the comments in here, you absolutely can,
如果你想阅读这里的所有注释的话，当然也可以
we're just gonna go ahead and delete them all.
但我们这里就把它们都直接删掉了
A quick keyboard shortcut is if you hit Command A or Ctrl, a,
有一个快捷键，如果你按下 "Command A" 或者 "Ctrl A"
you'll highlight all the text in your file,
就可以选中文件内的全部文本
and we're going to go ahead and delete it all.
然后我们把它们全部删除
So now we're just going to start from scratch here.
现在我们要从头开始
Now the setup for our deploy script in here is going to look really similar to the setup of our deploy script. From our previous section,
现在我们要配置的部署脚本和我们上一节配置的部署脚本很相似
we're going to do imports at the top,
我们要在顶部进行导入
we're going to have our async main function,
这里有一个异步的 main 函数
and then we're going to call the main function.
最后是调用这个 main 函数
So let's go ahead and define our main function,
让我们继续，来定义我们的 main 函数
we'll call it async. function main, like that,
输入 "async function main()" 就像这样
and then we'll call our main function.
然后我们要调用我们的 main 函数
And if you want to just copy paste this from the last section, you absolutely can.
如果你想的话，复制粘贴我们上一节的内容也是可以的
So we'll domain that then. Boom,
我们输入 "main().then()"
just like that.
就像这样
And because of these semicolons are going to drive me absolutely insane.
这堆分号会让我彻底疯掉
We're also going to add prettier, and our solidity prettier plugins.
因此我们要添加 "prettier" 和 "solidity prettier" 插件
So we'll do yarn, add dash dash Dev, prettier and prettier, plug in solidity.
所以我们要 "yarn add --dev prettier" 以及 "prettier-plugin-solidity"
Then we can go ahead and create our dot prettier, rc file,
接着创建我们的 ".prettierrc" 文件
we're going to add tab with four, use tabs, false,
我们要添加 "tabWidth: 4" 还有 "useTabs: false"
semi false, and then single quote, also false.
"semi: false" 最后是 "singleQuote: false"
Now we're going to be using this prettier rc file setup a lot.
现在我们用这个 prettierrc 文件设置了很多东西
So in future sections, if you want to just copy paste it, you can absolutely do that as well.
在之后的章节中，你可以直接从这复制粘贴
We're also going to add a dot prettier, ignore,
我们还要添加一个 ".prettierignore"
which tells prettier not to format some files, which we want,
它告诉 prettier 不要格式化哪些文件，只要我们想的话
we don't want prettier to spend a ton of time formatting all of our files,
我们不想让 prettier 花费过多的时间去格式化所有的文件
I'm just going to copy paste from the GitHub repo.
我直接从 GitHub 仓库中复制粘贴了这些过来
So feel free to copy paste from the GitHub repo as well,
你也可以这样，从 GitHub 仓库中直接复制粘贴过来
you'd find all the code for this section, like I said, in the GitHub repo associated with this course.
你可以在课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中找到本章节的全部代码
Now, unlike in our last section,
现在，与上一节不同的地方是
where we had to grab our contract code a little bit more manually,
我们不再需要手动获取我们的代码
with hard hat, it's actually a number of different ways to grab compiled contracts.
Hardhat 有多种不同的方法可以获取已编译的合约
The first way we're going to do it, we're actually going to use ethers.
第一件要做的事，是使用 ethers
And now this is where one of the first confusing changes actually comes in.
那么第一个容易让人感到困惑的变化来了
Previously, we did const ethers equals require ethers.
之前我们的做法是 "const  = require("ethers")"
And that was how we went ahead and worked with ethers.
这就是我们使用 ethers 的方法
However, you'll notice in our dev dependencies,
然而，你会注意到在我们的 "devDependencies" 中
we have this dependency called Hard Hat ethers.
有一个依赖项是 "hardhat-ethers"
Hard Hat ethers is a package that actually wraps hard hat with its own built in ethers.
"Hardhat-ethers" 是一个将 ethers 内置进了 Hardhat 的一个封装包
This is really advantageous
这种做法很有优势
because it allows hard hat to keep track of different deployments at different scripts and all these other things for us.
因为它允许 Hardhat 在不同脚本和其它情况下追踪不同的部署
So instead of importing ethers directly from ethers,
所以不要直接从 ethers 中导入 ethers
we're actually going to import ethers directly from hard hat instead.
而是要从 "hardhat" 中导入 ethers
This might seem a little confusing at first,
可能一开始会让人感到有些疑惑
but just know if we want to work with ethers and heart it,
但现在只用知道，如果我们要同时使用 ethers 和 Hardhat
it's usually much better to pull it in from heart and
那么通常从 Hardhat 中导入会是更好的选择
you can still do this and ethers will still work the same.
你仍然可以这样做，ethers 同样可以正常工作
But hard hat won't necessarily know about different contract factories in different pieces
但 Hardhat 就无法知道不同的代码中有不同的合约工厂了
and, and you'll see that in action in a second.
你很快就会看到这种情况
Now that we're pulling in ethers,
现在我们已经导入了 ethers
we can actually immediately grab a contract factory using ethers.
我们可以立即使用 ethers 获取一个合约工厂
We can say const simple storage factory
我们写下 "const SimpleStorageFactory "
equals await ethers dot get contract. Factory simple storage.
"= await ethers.getContractFactory('SimpleStorage')"
So in order to get a simple storage, contract factory,
所以为了获取一个 "SimpleStorage" 合约工厂
we can just do await ethers dot get contract factory.
我们就可以这样做 "await ethers.getContractFactory"
Now if we pulled right from ethers,
现在如果我们直接从 ethers 中导入
the package ethers doesn't know about this contracts folder
ethers 包并不知道有这个 "contracts" 文件夹
and ethers doesn't know we've already compiled simple storage dot soul.
它也不知道我们已经把 "SimpleStorage.sol" 编译好了
And it's in our artifacts.
就放在 "artifacts" 文件夹内
Hard Hat, on the other hand, does know about the contracts folder
另一方面 Hardhat 却知道 "contracts" 文件夹的存在
and does know that it's already compiled,
也知道它已经被编译好了
which is why this simple storage factory grabbing work so well.
这就是为什么这个 "SimpleStorageFactory" 的获取工作能做得如此出色
Once we have our factory here,
一旦我们拥有了这个工厂
we can do the same thing that we did in our previous section and deploy the contract.
我们就可以重复上一节中做过的事并部署合约
So we'll do a quick console dot log. Deploy flooring, contract done,
我们快速写一下 "console.log('Deploying contract...')"
and then we'll do Kant's simple storage equals await simple store edge factory dot deploy
接着是 "const simpleStorage = await SimpleStorageFactory.deploy()"
And boom, with that little bit of code, we're already able to deploy our simple storage contract,
Boom 有了这些代码，我们就已经可以部署我们的 "SimpleStorage" 合约了
then to wait to make sure it gets deployed,
然后需要等待以确保它部署成功
we can do await, simple storage, deployed. And that's it.
我们可以输入 "await simpleStorage.deployed()" 就是这样
Now let's see what happens when we go ahead and run this deploy script.
现在让我们看一下运行这个部署脚本时会发生什么
As you know, in our last section,
如你所知，在上一节中
we had to put in a private key, and we had to put an RPC URL.
我们需要输入一个私钥和一个 "RPC URL"
Right now, we don't have either one of those defined.
但现在我们没有定义二者中的任何一个
So what do you think should the script actually work?
那么你认为这个脚本能正常工作么？
Or do you think it'll break
还是说你认为它会报错？
because we, we didn't define what blockchain we're going to deploy you. We also didn't find a private key.
因为我们没有定义要部署到哪个区块链上，也没有定义私钥
Well, let's go ahead and try this out.
好吧，让我们来试试看吧
We can run the script in our terminal by running yarn, hard hat, run, scripts slash deploy dot j, s.
我们在终端中运行这个脚本，用 "yarn hardhat run scripts/deploy.js"
And again, I'm hitting tab here to do a little auto completion
这里我再一次使用了 tab 键进行了补全操作
and see what happens.
让我们看看发生了什么
Well, we got deploying contract, it says done, but that's really it.
好了，我们已经把合约部署好了，它说已经完成了，事实就是如此
So what really happened? Well, let's add one more line in here.
所以它到底是怎么做到的？让我们在这里再添加一行
Let's do console dot log. We'll do some string interpolation deployed, contract to.
内容是 "console.log()"，再插入一些字符串 "Deployed contract to"
And then we'll add simple storage. That address.
并且添加 "simpleStorage.address"
Let's run this now. We get deployed contract,
现在再运行一次，我们已经成功部署了合约
and then we get deployed contract to, and then we get a contract address.
并且得到了 "Deploy contract to" 还有一个合约地址
Hmm, what's going on here.
哈！到底是发生了什么？